Ayton MacEachern B.FS, CFPR, CIM

Also Available to Contract as 8 10 Industries

PO Box 1034 · Acme, AB TOM 0A0

aytonmaceachern@me.com · 587-973-3239

Summary

Motivated and skilled Alberta University Graduate, and Journeyman/Red Seal/Blue Seal Welder; with a diverse experiential history, and a focus on training and development.

Hobbies include automotive fabrication, programming and playing video games, and backcountry hiking and skiing. Please see http://bit.ly/810portfolio for a sample of my automotive fabrication experience.

Education

Blue Seal Certification - Alberta Industry Training

NAIT - Welder Apprenticeship Technical Training

NAIT - Welding Technician Certificate

Mount Royal College - Bachelor of Applied Financial Services

Bev Facey Community High School – Alberta High School Diploma

Certifications, Designations

Certified Financial Planner (CFPR) – Canadian Financial Planners Standards Council

Canadian Investment Manager (CIM) - Canadian Securities Institute

Current Welding Certifications

ABSA Initial B Pressure

Expired Welding Certifications (available to re-certify)

Nickel Alloy P4x GTAW/SMAW Performance Qualification F5/F6, Stainless Steel GTAW/SMAW Performance Qualification F5/F6, Carbon Steel GTAW/SMAW Performance Qualification F5/F4, Small Bore SMAW Performance Qualification Downhill F3/Uphill F4, Small Bore SMAW Performance Qualification Uphill F3/F4 Max Thickness, CWB Flat Spot F3 SMAW ("Q" Deck Welder), CWB All Position FCAW, CWB All Position SMAW

Current Safety Tickets

Construction Safety Training System (CSTS-09)

OSSA Regional Orientation

Basic Rigging

WHMIS Awareness

Transportation of Dangerous Goods

Experience Highlights

CRAZY 8 VENTURES INC. (Owner) (December 2016 – January 2020)

Spud Farm Esports Academy – Started and ran the first esports academy in Western Canada, using video games to aid behavior challenged youth (particularly ones with ADHD, ODD, and Autism Spectrum Disorder) with anger and stress management. In 2019 we expanded to include after school care, and home-school computer science programs.

Welder - During my time as a welder, I trained many new comers to the trade, and officially apprenticed 3.

CRAZY 8 WELDING INC. (Rig Welder / Owner- Operator) - Enerkem Alberta BioFuels Phase 2 – Edmonton, AB (September 2016 – October 2016)

WAIWARD STEEL (May – June 2015, June – August 2016) - CNRL Horizon - OPP Shutdown ('15), Suncor Fort Hills OPP New Construction ('16)

LEDER STEEL (August 2015 – June 2016) - CNRL Horizon - Super Pot & OPP Pump Station Pipe Rack Modification, Trans Alta Keephills - Sodium BiCarbonate Injection Test Project, Mayfair Building – Edmonton, AB, Kelly Ramsey Tower – Edmonton, AB

MACDOUGALL STEEL ERECTORS INC. (November 2014 – December 2014) - Devon Energy Pike Lodge - Conklin, AB, Various Fabrication of Skids/Frames – Xzact Yard, Edmonton, AB

BIG COUNTRY ENERGY SERVICES LP (September 2014 – November 2014) - ATCO Cloverbar, Salt Caverns, Camelback – Strathcona County, AB, General Spool Fabrication – Big Country Yard, Ponoka, AB

CLEARSTREAM ENERGY SERVICES LTD (October 2013- – September 2014) - Gibsons Hardisty Unit Rail Connection - Hardisty, AB, Gibsons Hardisty East Terminal Expansion – Hardisty, AB

ARNETT & BURGESS OILFIELD CONSTRUCTION LIMITED (October 2013) - Keyera 32km Mainline – Rimbey, AB, ConocoPhillips Riser Fabrication - Ponoka County, AB

Financial Planner (Certified Financial Planner^R)

MacEachern & Associates (Owner - Fee Based Financial Planner) (August 2009 – October 2013) - Used this opportunity to educate my clients to become empowered to regain control of their own financial future.

Investors Group (Consultant) (September 2007 – January 2008)

Senior Financial Editor

Investopedia.com / Forbes.com (January 2008 – August 2009) - Started in 2007 as a financial writer, with duties such as writing definitions in the ever-changing financial landscape of the time. Worked myself into the Senior Financial Editor role, where I oversaw a team of over 20 writers and 4 editors who wrote articles, definitions, answered visitor questions, and was lead hand in bringing video education to the website.

Cook

Joey Tomatoes Kitchen (Sous Chef) (September 2002 – September 2003) - Managed, and trained a prep kitchen of 5 cooks, was responsible for inventory management including all supplier communications

Chateau Lake Louise (Fairmont Hotels) (2nd Cook) (May – August 2002)

Earl's Restaurants (Sous Chef) (Sept 1998 – May 2002)